THIS STORY IS A FICION,
（本作所有人物、組織名均為虛構）
MOREOVER, THE STORY HAS NO RELATION TO REAL-LIFE INCIDENTS AND EVENTS.
（與任何特定事件或現象無關）
What's wrong, Lihaku? Concentrate!
怎麼了，李白？專心點
Right. Sorry.
是，抱歉
You're cleaning?
打掃？
You don't need to do it yourself.
小姑娘不用特地打掃呀
We can ask someone else…
-只要拜託其他人… -拜託其他人
In the court medical office,
聽說宮廷的尚藥局
there were some physicians whose salaries were cut
貌似因為藥材的管理不周
because they failed to manage the medicine properly.
而有個醫官受到減俸的處罰哦？
You have to clean up before it gets too humid.
若不快在濕氣加重前清理乾淨的話
You'll regret it later.
可是會後悔莫及的
Yes, ma'am.
是
We're almost done.
終於告一段落了
Sweets are the best for when you're tired!
累的時候就是該吃甜食呢
This guy is super rich, huh?
這位大叔真是個大少爺
You can rarely find sweet potatoes at this time of year.
不僅能拿出這個季節很少見的地瓜
And he uses paper for plates like it's nothing…
還理所當然地拿紙當盤子…
-This is some nice paper. -Can you tell?
-這紙品質很好呢 -哦，看得出來嗎？
My family back home organizes the whole village to make these.
我老家集合了全村一起造紙
They're purveyors that make paper for the court!
是進獻給宮廷的御用商人呢
-Impressive, huh? -Yes, that's impressive.
-很厲害吧？ -很厲害呢
I wonder if he can get me a friends-only discount.
這能不能用熟人的價格算便宜點？
Back then,
以前啊
the more paper we made, the richer we got.
只要造出越多紙就能賺越多
We did a lot of exporting to other countries,
由於大量向國外出口
so I could get all the sweets I wanted when I was a kid!
所以我小的時候 想買多少喜歡的點心都行呢
But,
不過
ever since the previous emperor's mother forbade cutting down trees,
先帝的母后禁止採伐樹木後
it didn't go so well.
就沒那麼順利了
We started using other materials, so trade started to fail.
我們開始用其他材料 結果連生意都一落千丈
Our family was blamed for this.
我們家族也因此被問責
We ran out of money, so my older sister went to the rear palace.
因為錢不夠用，所以我姊姊進了後宮
When even my younger sister offered to go,
後來連妹妹都說她要進宮
I decided to come here instead.
只好由我代替她進宮了
There are never enough eunuchs, so we got paid more that way.
宦官向來更缺人手 所以賣了個好價錢呢
In the end, I never did see my older sister.
到頭來也沒再見到姊姊就是了
He's had more struggles than I thought.
想不到他吃了這麼多苦呢
Excuse me. I'm here to finish cleaning.
打擾了，我來繼續打掃了
Oh, it's you, miss.
哦，是小姑娘啊
I got a letter from my younger sister.
這是舍妹寄來的信
The court might stop using our paper.
我家的紙恐怕要失去御用品的地位了
True, this isn't high quality enough to be used in the court.
這種紙質確實是不夠格賣到宮廷裡
Losing the title of court purveyor
有沒有御用商人的頭銜
could really impact sales.
會大幅影響今後的銷量
I wonder why.
怎麼會這樣呢？
They worked hard so that they could make more paper than before.
明明之前才說過 好不容易能造出更多紙的啊
Did they cut down on some the steps to be able to make more?
能造出更多紙 是因為節省了作法嗎？
We'd never do something like that!
我們才不會那麼做呢
We started having cows handle some of the labor.
我們是用牛來代勞需要力氣的工作
We haven't changed materials or the process at all.
材料和作法都和以前一樣的
I guess we won't be cleaning today.
看樣子今天無法打掃了呢
Unlike some low-quality items you can find in shops,
與市面上流通的劣質品不同
there are no impurities,
既沒有雜質
the fibers are crushed down evenly, and the thickness is even.
纖維也搗碎的很均勻，厚度相當一致
The problem is the scuffing on the surface, and…
問題是這表面起的細毛和…
the durability!
強度
And what is the process?
以前的作法是如何呢？
It's just regular paper-making.
就和一般的造紙方式一樣
But we have our own special way of crushing materials
不過我們家在搗碎材料
and creating the glue…
及製作紙藥上有獨家秘方 這部分可不能告訴你
So even he doesn't overshare trade secrets.
這種事情就不會說溜嘴呢
Do you use special water too?
水之類的也有講究嗎？
Yes. We draw spring water
有，為了讓紙藥適度凝固
so that the glue hardens properly.
我們有汲取泉水
It's to maintain a certain level of humidity.
這是為了要調整濕度
I can't say any more than that.
再來就是秘密了
Cow… Spring water…
牛，還有汲取的泉水…
Lightning bolt!
靈光一閃！
Do you simmer rice-soaked water to make the glue?
紙藥是用洗米水之類煮成的嗎？
No, we mix flour and water.
不，我們是老實地用小麥粉溶解做的
Otherwise, it won't harden properly…
不然會不容易凝固…
Miss, will you forget what I just said?
小姑娘，剛剛的話能請你忘掉嗎？
Certainly.
好哦
And where do you keep the cows?
那麼，你們把牛養在哪裡？
I don't know about those details.
這種事情我就不太清楚了
I see.
這樣啊
Here you are.
請用
Arrowroot tea?
葛湯嗎？
Miss, you messed up the measurements.
小姑娘，你這份量調錯了
It's stuck to the cup. I can't drink it.
都黏在茶碗上了，喝不了呀
I'm sorry.
不好意思
I'll tell you how you can drink this more easily.
我這就教您方便飲用的方法
Will you follow my steps?
能請您照著做嗎？
Lick your spoon, and mix. You repeat that many times.
像這樣用舔過的湯匙 加以攪拌，然後重複幾次
Isn't this bad manners?
感覺有些不雅呢
-Hey, the thickness is gone. -Right?
-哎呀，沒那麼濃稠了 -對吧？
Arrowroot tea and glue are similar, don't you think?
葛湯和紙藥很像吧？
They're not dissimilar. Maybe once you mix in saliva
是有點像，假如混入口水的話
the glue won't be thick anymore.
紙藥說不定也會失去濃稠度呢
You're exactly right.
就是這麼回事
What are you saying?
什麼這麼回事？
This quack is really dense.
庸醫也太遲鈍了吧？
Cows have a lot of saliva in their mouths.
牛的嘴裡有很多口水吧？
Maybe you could check where the cows are drinking water.
以防萬一 確認一下牛在哪裡喝水如何？
I have to write to my sister!
我得趕快給妹妹寫信！
I'll be going now.
我今天就先告辭了
I'm back.
我回來了
Hey, Maomao.
哎呀，貓貓
I got a message for you to come immediately.
有人捎來消息，要你馬上過去
Where is the meeting place?
地點在哪裡？
How much does it cost to buy out a courtesan?
娼妓的贖金要多少才夠？
I thought this was about Suirei.
我還以為是要說翠苓的事情
He's truly an incompetent dog.
真是頭笨狗啊
Listen to this, miss!
你聽我說啊，小姑娘
I went to the Verdigris House
我前一陣子去綠青館
and heard one of the Three Princesses is being bought out!
聽說三姬之一要被贖走了
That's why he's worried about Big Sis Pairin.
所以是在擔心白鈴姐姐啊
There's a huge range in prices.
價格有高有低呢
What's the highest price?
超一流的呢？
All right, I'll tell you.
我明白了
Market price can change, so it's only a general estimate.
總之，行情得看時價 所以也只能當個標準
I want a straightforward answer.
請你直接告訴我吧
How much?
要多少錢？
It's hard to say.
很難說呢
Prices are decided by how much the courtesan would make at the brothel
贖身金是倒推娼妓 還能在青樓賺多少年
if she weren't bought out, with some extra money added.
加上一點小錢後算出金額
Sometimes, they will even double the price.
然後再加上一倍就是價格了
Miss…
小姑娘…
If Big Sis Pairin were to be bought out, there are two candidates
如果要被贖走的是白鈴姐姐
who are old regulars.
老熟客裡有兩個人選
Two?
兩個人？
The first is an Old Master of a merchant family.
其中一人是貿易商行的大老闆
He's a good-natured old man who continued to come even when we were struggling.
是在綠青館慘澹之時 也仍照樣光顧的和藹老爺
Another is a high-ranking official who is her regular.
另一位則是高官貴客
He's still young, in his early thirties.
還很年輕，才剛過三十歲
Apparently, they're very compatible in bed,
作為夜晚交歡的對象似乎相當合拍
but a point of concern is how tired he looks the next day.
但隔天會略顯疲憊這點 讓人有些在意
Considering the kind of life she'd live after being bought out,
考慮到贖身後的生活
neither is perfect.
不論哪位都…
Tired? What do you mean?
疲憊？什麼意思？
Big Sis Pairin is known for not only being good at dance,
白鈴姐姐不僅擅長舞蹈
but for always winning in bed.
在夜晚同時也未嘗一敗而聞名
When she feels unfulfilled, she will try to seduce anybody and everybody.
要是欲求不滿，就會對任何人出手
She's a nymphomaniac.
換言之，就是個色魔
No!
不要！
But…
不過…
But?
不過？
The people who took care of me
在老爹收養我之前
at the Verdigris House until Old Man took me in
在綠青館照顧我的
were Grams and the Three Princesses.
就是老鴇和三姬
And Big Sis Pairin,
特別是
who had the special condition of being able to breastfeed
沒有生育經驗，但體質特殊
despite never having her own children,
能分泌母乳的姐姐
is the closest thing I have to a mother.
是最接近母親的存在
I'm not sure what Big Sis thinks of this,
雖然不曉得姐姐怎麼想
but when I think back to those days, I feel a wasted potential.
但想起那些日子，總覺得有些惋惜
She's a woman with a lot of lust,
雖然她是性慾較強的女子
but she has just as much maternal instinct.
但也有著不相上下的母性
But… what?
不過…怎麼樣？
Sir Lihaku loves Big Sis while fully understanding what her job is.
李白大人
He is an incompetent dog, but he's an earnest man,
雖有點像頭笨狗，但骨子裡相當老實
and he's a lovable idiot
能為了女人出人頭地
who's working to climb the ranks for a woman.
也有著討喜的傻氣之處
And, he has a lot of stamina.
更重要的是，體力充沛無比
He's not a bad candidate to buy her out.
作為贖身對象並不差
Sir Lihaku.
李白大人
How much do you get paid as a salary?
您的俸祿是多少呢？
How is this relevant?
怎麼突然問這個？
About 800 silvers?
一年八百銀兩嗎？
-Hey, now. -1,200 silvers, then?
-喂 -那是一千二囉？
About 1,000 silvers a year, it looks like.
看來大概是一年千枚銀兩吧
-It's not enough? -Not at all.
-不夠嗎？ -不夠
You'd want at least 10,000 upfront.
最好是有現款一萬
-Ten thousand? -Huh?
-一萬？ -怎麼了？
A cheap courtesan would be 400,
便宜的娼妓只要四百
but one of the Three Princesses of the Verdigris House
但要是綠青館三姬之一的話
would be at least 10,000 silvers.
少說也要準備一萬才行
Ten thousand…
一萬…
Hey.
我說
If I were to scrounge up 10,000,
要是我能籌到一萬
would I be able to buy her out?
你覺得能夠成功贖身嗎？
You mean, would you get ruthlessly rejected by Big Sis?
李白大人是說 有沒有可能被姐姐狠狠拒絕嗎？
It can't be helped.
真是沒辦法
Sir Lihaku, can you take off your clothes?
李白大人，能請您把衣服脫了嗎？
I won't get rejected if I take my clothes off?
脫了就不會被拒絕嗎？
The only thing I'm certain of
我只是知道
is the kind of body Big Sis Pairin prefers.
白鈴姐姐喜好的身體罷了
And your bottoms too.
下面也請脫了吧
-Do I have to? -You have to.
-下面也要？ -下面也要
Once you strip, raise both hands to your shoulders
脫了之後，將雙手舉高到肩膀的位置
and make a fist, please.
然後做出使力的動作
Like this?
這樣嗎？
Big Sis has an appetite and would eat anything,
白鈴姐姐雖然是來者不拒的貪吃鬼
but she does have personal taste.
但還是有自己的偏好
This is impressive.
這可真是…
Now, lower your arms and make a fist.
接著把手放下來，然後使力
Like this?
-這樣嗎？ -哦
He's a military man, so he's well-trained.
不愧是武官，鍛鍊得非常強健
His muscles are impressive.
真是好肌肉
Maybe it could work.
這樣說不定能行呢
Up next…
再來就是…
Please take off your last article of clothing!
那麼，請大人脫掉最後一件吧！
You two, what are you doing?
你們兩個到底在做什麼？
How do you do,
近來可好？
Sir Jinshi?
壬氏大人
What were you doing?
你這傢伙剛才在做什麼？
Beautiful people are scary when they get mad.
美人生起氣來還真可怕
I don't know what to tell you.
要說是在做什麼的話
I was called upon, and was providing advice about something.
小的只是被傳喚 接著商量了一些事情
Why was that man making that pose?
那個男人為何會是那副模樣？
It's nothing suspicious.
小的並沒有做虧心事
I was just studying it closely.
只是仔細地欣賞而已
What?
什麼？
You were studying it closely?
你說仔細地…欣賞嗎？
Yes, I was just looking.
是，只是欣賞而已
-For what purpose? -Why do you ask?
-為了什麼？ -要說為了什麼
To determine if he has a favorable body type,
若要檢查身體是否符合喜好
the easiest way is to look at the real thing.
親眼確認是最好的方法吧？
A favorable body type?
你說喜好的身體？
Yes.
對
Appearances are only a part of what makes a person,
雖然外觀只是人的一項要素
but the more favorable, the better.
但能符合喜好當然最好
I was going to check his most important area
最後只要確認最重要的部分
to determine how to convince Big Sis…
再來就是思考如何向姐姐美言兩句了
And how was his appearance?
那麼，那個男人的外觀如何？
He had a well-balanced body.
他的肉體十分勻稱
He looked to be a diligent man who trains without rest every day,
看得出來是每日鍛鍊 從不偷懶的認真人物
and I'm sure he's one of the most skilled soldiers as well.
在武官當中 想必也算是相當了得的人士吧
You can see what kind of person someone is
你光看一個人的身體
just by looking at their body?
就能知道他的為人嗎？
Lifestyle habits are visible in someone's body.
生活習慣會如實地表現在身體上
If you're an apothecary,
身為藥師
clients often don't share their lives with you.
也會遇到不願多談自己事情的客人
It's an important skill.
因此自然就學會了
So you could figure me out by looking at my body?
你看我的身體也看得出來嗎？
What?
什麼？
Could it be,
該不會…
he's jealous of Sir Lihaku?
他在嫉妒李白大人吧？
What a proud man.
這男人真是…
He wants to show off and say he's more beautiful!
竟然想要炫耀自己比別人好看！
I know he has a beautiful body.
我知道你有一副俊美的身體
It was more muscular than I expected.
實際上，還出乎意料地緊實健壯
But…
不過
There's no point in me looking at your body.
就算看了壬氏大人的身體 也沒有任何意義
Unfortunately, I don't think you'd pair well with my Big Sister.
很遺憾，小的並不認為您適合姐姐
What?
什麼？
What am I doing?
在我做這些事情的時候
Pairin might be getting bought out at this very moment!
白鈴很可能已經被贖走了也不一定
But I have no power to do anything
但現在的我
right now!
什麼都辦不到
Pairin…
白鈴
What's going on?
現在是什麼狀況？
If I remember correctly, his name is Jinshi.
我記得他叫壬氏
Some rumor him to be the Emperor's lover.
有傳聞說他是皇帝的男寵
Thanks for entertaining my maid the other day.
前些日子，我的婢女受你照顧了
It was nothing.
不，擔當不起…
I heard that
聽說
you're in love with someone right now.
你現在好像有意中人啊？
What?
咦？
Did that girl tell him?
莫非是小姑娘告訴他的嗎？
Is that why he's smiling so much at me?
所以他才這樣一直對著我笑嗎？
He's already been called
以他這麼年輕
the most beautiful person in the country at his young age.
有著人稱本國第一的美貌
If he's a lover for royalty,
還有受到器重的地位
it must sound silly to him to buy out a courtesan.
為娼妓贖身的事 恐怕不過是個笑話而已
It's fine if he makes fun of me.
想取笑我也沒關係
But if he's making fun of Pairin, then I won't keep quiet.
但要是想取笑白鈴就另當別論
If he means to insult her…
如果他膽敢侮辱她…
Twenty thousand.
兩萬
If I offered to loan you money to buy her out, would you accept?
如果我說贖金由我替你付 你覺得如何？
What do you mean by that?
這話是什麼意思？
I mean exactly what I said.
就是這個意思
I'm very grateful for your offer,
雖然您這話讓我很高興
but is this something you can say
但對一位素不相識的官員
to an official who you've never met?
突然說出這種話是否妥當？
My cat is very suspicious, you see.
我那裡的貓戒心可是很強的
But she's helping you with your problem,
但她卻同意和你商量
and she's assessing whether you're a worthy partner
甚至還考慮讓你成為她
for her sister.
有如親姐之人的丈夫
So you're saying, if your cautious cat trusts me,
您的意思是 個性謹慎的貓願意親近我
you know I'm a principled person…
表示我也是值得信任的人嗎？
Did I say something to upset him?
我說錯了什麼嗎？
I heard about you from your acquaintances.
我從旁人聽到了些你的事情
You're the son of a regional official,
雖說是地方官的子弟
but I'm sure you struggled with becoming a soldier in the capital.
但要在京城當上武官 想必是相當辛苦吧？
I heard that an observant soldier saw your potential, and appointed you
聽說你受到善於識人的軍師賞識
to lead your squad.
指派你統領一隊？
Yes, sir.
是
He saw through the official explanation,
表面上明明是一位小隊長辭退
which is that the squad leader quit.
才讓我遞補上去的
I'm sure it's normal to want to befriend a talented official
誰都會想和前途無量的官員
with a lot of potential.
打好關係吧？
Even so, 20,000 silvers is too high a price for the return.
就算如此，兩萬銀兩也太過大方了
I only really need half,
我只需要一半
or even a quarter of the offer amount.
不，四分之一就夠了
I'm honestly very happy that you see my potential,
老實說，您願意幫忙出錢 下官確實非常開心
and to be frank, your offer is extremely tempting to me.
下官也恨不得能接受您的好意
Even so, I can't accept your silver.
但是，就這件事 下官不能收下您的銀兩
For you, it might just be a courtesan,
對您來說，她或許不過是個娼妓
but for me, she's the only woman I want.
但對下官而言，她是絕無僅有的女子
If I want her as a wife,
想要迎娶為妻的女子
but can't buy her out with my own money,
若不能靠自己賺的錢替她贖身
how can I call myself a man?
那還算得上是男人嗎？
I see. I'm sorry about that.
原來如此，是我失禮了
-What? -I might want…
-什麼？ -今後
To talk to you at a later date.
我可能還會有事找你商量
Would that be fine?
你不介意吧？
Yes, sir!
遵命
-Sir Jinshi. -Yeah.
-壬氏大人 -嗯
Looks like there's no need to worry.
看來無需擔心了
What the hell was that?
這到底是怎麼回事？
What should I do?
這下該怎麼辦呢？
I guess I can start
總而言之
by showing off what I can do at the next training session.
下次訓練時稍微表現一下好了
Or maybe, I'll ask for more work.
或是請長官多派點差事吧
No. All right.
不，好吧
I don't know when I'll see her next, but I'll write to her.
先寄封信給 不知何時才能相見的女子吧
I shouldn't just buy her out without telling her.
不是單方面的迎娶
I'll ask how she feels.
要問過她的意願才行
Maybe she'll respond with social pleasantries.
即使回覆是客套話也好
I'll just have to believe in them to work hard every day.
我願意相信它，當成每日奮鬥的動力
I'll just walk the path I chose for myself!
堅持自己相信的道路前進吧
Grams is saying a whole bunch of things,
婆婆雖然說了些什麼
but I intend on working for much longer.
但我可還風華正茂呢
I'm still waiting
而且我啊
for some prince to come for me and take me away.
還等著有朝一日 從某個地方來的王子大人來迎娶我呢
That's what I thought.
雖然早就有這種感覺了
As long as Big Sis Pairin likes him,
只要能贏得白鈴姐姐的芳心
he doesn't need to pay 10,000 silvers.
那麼贖金就不需要到一萬銀兩
All he needs now is luck.
剩下就是運氣了
That man came again to discuss buying out a courtesan.
應該是那個人來談到贖身的事情
I think that's what caused the misunderstanding.
讓見習娼妓小丫頭誤會了吧
"That man…"
“那個人…”
Sir Lakan.
羅漢大人
I looked all over for you.
原來您在這裡啊
Sir Lakan, the meeting is about to start.
羅漢大人，會議要開始了
A blue rose.
藍色的玫瑰
What is that?
那是什麼？
PREVIEW OF NEXT EPISODE
（下集預告）
Next Episode, "Blue Roses."
下一集，《藍色的玫瑰》
Subtitle translation by: Yukimi Ohashi
字幕翻譯：楊易